<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node unique_id="61" master_id="0" name="Spring Ashok It" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="0" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1720215527" ts_lastsave="1720263752">
    <rich_text>Spring framework introductin
===================


Programming Language

Core Java (Language Syntaxes, fundamentals)

-&gt; Using this core java we will build GUI/CUI based application

&gt; Graphical User Interface

&gt; Commandline User Interface (CLI)

-&gt; Adv Java

	JDBC : Database Connectivity -&gt; APi

	Servlets: Web applications developement -&gt; web techonology

	JSP: Web pages development  -&gt; web techonology

→ Frameworks

	Struts -&gt; controller layer only we build

	Hibernate -&gt; persitence only DB

	Spring Framework -&gt; application framework end to end app.
	
-&gt; Framework is a semi 	 software which provides some common logics which are required for applications development

	load jdbc driver
	get connection
	create stmt
	execute query
	close connection
	
	application to database


-&gt; Frameworks are divided into 2 types	

	1) ORM Framework

	2) Web Framework

-&gt; ORM (Object Relational Mapping) frameworks are used to develop Persistence Layer in applications.

	Ex: Hibernate
	
-&gt; Web frameworks are used to develop Web applications

	Ex: Struts	
	</rich_text>
    <rich_text justification="left"></rich_text>
    <rich_text>
	
-&gt; Spring is an application development framework.
-› Spring is Non Invasive framework. Spring it will not force the programmer to extend/implement any framework related classes and interfaces.
-&gt; By Using Spring framework we can develop End to End application.
</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="small">-&gt; Spring is versatile framework. Spring can be integrated with any other framework which is available in the market.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="small">-&gt; Spring is loosely coupled framework. It is developed in modular fashion.</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
-&gt; Spring is not a single framework. It is collection of frameworks.

-&gt; Spring framework is developed in Modular Fashion.

		-&gt; Spring Core
		-&gt; Spring Context
		-&gt; Spring AOP
		-&gt; Spring DAO
		-&gt; Spring Web MVC
		-&gt; Spring ORM
		
-&gt; Spring Core is Base Module for Spring Framework. This module providing fundamental concepts of Spring they are IOC and DI.&#13;
			IOC: Inversion of Control&#13;
			DI: Dependency Injection
			&#13;
-&gt; Spring Context module will take care of Configurations required in our applications.
&#13;
-&gt; Spring AOP module is used to seperate business logic and secondary logic in our application.

	Aspect Oriented Programming
	&#13;
-&gt; Spring DAO/Spring JDBC module is used to develop Persistence Layer. Spring JDBC module is developed on top of JDBC api.
&#13;
-&gt; Spring Web MVC module is used to web applications.
&#13;
Spring ORM module is used to develop Persistence Layer.&#13;
	ORM&gt; Object Relational Mapping
	&#13;
It is used to represent data in the form of objects
</rich_text>
    <encoded_png char_offset="1054" justification="left" link="" sha256sum="bc0ccdfca31c4737f5132739e1d8eb25770247873a2d89d1e663858f65c93965"/>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
