<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node unique_id="52" master_id="0" name="Class &amp; methods" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="0" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1718752242" ts_lastsave="1720555345">
    <rich_text>
  User Side

1.  User Management 
     - UserController
     - createUser
     - authenticateUser
     - logout

2.  Order Management 
     - OrderController
     - createOrder
     - addOrderItem
     - getOrder

3.  Shipment Management 
     - ShipmentController
     - getShipment
     - getTrackingInfo

  Admin Side

1.  User Management 
   - UserController
     - assignRole

2.  Inventory Management 
   - InventoryController
     - addProduct
     - updateInventory
     - getProduct

3.  Shipment Management 
   - ShipmentController
     - createShipment
     - updateShipmentStatus

4.  Tracking and Monitoring 
   - TrackingController
     - logTrackingInfo

5.  Billing and Invoicing 
   - BillingController
     - createInvoice
     - processPayment
     - getInvoice










  User-Side Modules (3 modules)

1.  User Management 
   - Handles user authentication, creation, and basic profile management.

2.  Order Management 
   - Allows users to create orders, add items to orders, and view their order history.

3.  Shipment Management 
   - Provides basic tracking information for shipments related to the user's orders.

  Admin-Side Modules (5 modules)

1.  User Management 
   - Admins can manage users, assign roles, and potentially deactivate or delete user accounts.

2.  Inventory Management 
   - Admins can add, update, and manage products in the inventory.

3.  Order Management 
   - Admins have additional capabilities to view and manage orders, such as editing or canceling orders.

4.  Shipment Management 
   - Admins can create shipments, update shipment statuses, and view detailed tracking information.

5.  Billing and Invoicing 
   - Admins can generate invoices, process payments, and manage billing-related tasks.

  Considerations for Production-Level Readiness

1.  Scalability : Ensure that the architecture and design can scale as the volume of users, orders, and transactions increases.

2.  Security : Implement robust security measures to protect user data, transactions, and system integrity.

3.  Performance : Optimize performance to handle concurrent user interactions, especially during peak times.

4.  Error Handling and Logging : Implement thorough error handling and logging mechanisms to facilitate troubleshooting and maintenance.

5.  Compliance : Ensure compliance with relevant regulations and standards, such as data protection laws (e.g., GDPR, CCPA).

6.  Testing : Conduct comprehensive testing, including unit testing, integration testing, and user acceptance testing, to ensure reliability and functionality.

  Additional Classes or Modules

Depending on the specific requirements and complexity of the logistics project, you may need to consider additional classes or modules, such as:

-  Customer Service : Handling customer inquiries, support tickets, and feedback.
  
-  Analytics and Reporting : Generating reports on sales, inventory levels, shipment statuses, etc., to support decision-making.

-  Integration with External Systems : Integration with ERP systems, shipping carriers, payment gateways, etc., to streamline operations.

-  Notifications and Alerts : Implementing notifications for order updates, shipment tracking, payment reminders, etc.

-  Localization : Support for multiple languages, currencies, and regional settings if operating internationally.

</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
