<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node unique_id="90" master_id="0" name="Spring MVC" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="220" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1720556470" ts_lastsave="1720785602">
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Spring MVC Overview</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">what</rich_text>
    <rich_text> is MVC?

Spring MVC is a framework for building </rich_text>
    <rich_text foreground="#c64600">web applications</rich_text>
    <rich_text> in Java, using the Model-View-Controller (MVC) pattern.

  Concepts Explained

1. Web Framework
   - A platform to develop and run web applications.

2. Model-View-Controller (MVC)
   - Model: Holds application data and business logic.
   - View: Displays data to the user (e.g., HTML, JSP, Thymeleaf).
   - Controller: Handles user input, updates Model and View.

3. Controllers
   - Classes annotated with @Controller.
   - Manage incoming web requests and return views.

4. Views (JSP, Thymeleaf)
   - Templates to render data into HTML.

5. Model and ModelMap
   - Model: Holds data for the view.
   - ModelMap: A map structure to pass data from controller to view.

6. Request Mappings
   - @RequestMapping: Maps HTTP requests to controller methods.

7. Form Handling
   - Manages form submissions and validates user input.

8. RESTful Web Services
   - Services that follow REST principles, using @RestController and @RequestMapping.

  </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Why These Concepts are Important</rich_text>
    <rich_text>

- Separation of Concerns: Divides the application into distinct sections (Model, View, Controller), making it easier to </rich_text>
    <rich_text foreground="#c64600">manage and maintain</rich_text>
    <rich_text>.
- Reusability: Components can be reused across the application.
- Scalability: Simplifies scaling the application by separating different concerns.

  </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Implementation</rich_text>
    <rich_text> Steps

1. Set up Spring MVC Project: Create a new Spring project using tools like Spring Boot.
2. Define Models: Create classes to represent the data.
3. Create Controllers: Write classes with @Controller to handle web requests.
4. Design Views: Use JSP, Thymeleaf, or other templating engines to create the user interface.
5. Map Requests: Use @RequestMapping to link web requests to controller methods.
6. Handle Forms: Manage user input through forms and validate data.

  </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Advantages</rich_text>
    <rich_text> of Spring MVC

- Modularity: Breaks application into modules.
- Testability: Easier to test components individually.
- Flexibility:Supports different types of user interfaces, such as mobile apps, desktop applications, and web pages.

  </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Disadvantages</rich_text>
    <rich_text> of Spring MVC

- Complexity: Can be complex for beginners.
- Configuration: Requires configuration, though Spring Boot simplifies it.

  </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Common Problems Resolved by Spring MVC</rich_text>
    <rich_text>

- Maintainability: Easier to maintain code with clear separation.
- Scalability: Supports scaling with modular design.
- Flexibility: Adapts to various view technologies and development needs.
   
   
	1.Spring MVC is a framework used to build web applications in Java using the Model-View-Controller (MVC) pattern.
	2.Spring MVC is important because dividing the application into different parts (Model, View, Controller) makes it easier to manage and maintain.and also
	3.Components can be reused within the application.
	4.It simplifies scaling the application by using different parts (Model, View, Controller).
	5.We can implement the MVC pattern by creating a Spring Boot project and adding the necessary dependencies, including the MVC starter. Then, we write entity, controller, and view classes. When a request comes into the controller, it handles the request and displays the data on the view page.
	6.	The main advantage of Spring MVC is that it breaks the application into modules,
	 7. Easier to test components individually.
	8.it supports various types of user interfaces, including desktop, mobile applications, and web applications
	</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
