<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node unique_id="57" master_id="0" name="webapp &amp; webservice" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="0" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1720193284" ts_lastsave="1720199601">
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Web Application:
-----------------------</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
	1.web application is a software application and it is runs on a web server and also it is  accessd  through a web browser over a network.
	2.components:
			frontend:user interface, usually developed using html,css,javascript
			backend:the server-side logic is responsible for processing request, intracting with databse, and generating dynamic content.
	3.Architecture:
		web application follow client-side architecture. client is typically browser and server is nothing but powerfull computer that stores web application files, database and also logic.
		request send -&gt; server process the request -&gt; return the response, from the server sends the request data like(images, html, json).
		large scale web appls contains presentaion layer, business layer, databse layer.
	4.Technologies
		framework like spring boot for java , django for python help to develop web appliation quickly by providing  pre-build tool and structures.
		Database intergration for web application like mysql, postsql
		
</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Web Service:
--------------------</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
	1.A web service is a type of software. and it is used to communicate machine-to-machine over a network. and also it provide </rich_text>
    <rich_text link="webs https://chatgpt.com/c/4c783710-8031-4a68-abed-a826c727d727" background="#3584e4" foreground="#ffffff" weight="heavy">functonality</rich_text>
    <rich_text> to other applications via standard web protocols.
	2.</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">SOAP</rich_text>
    <rich_text>(simple object Access protocol) : it produce data xml format and also HTTP &amp; SMTP for message transmission. 
	3.</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">REST</rich_text>
    <rich_text>(Representational state Transfer): Uses standard HTTP methods (GET,POST,PUT,DELETE) and data exchange for JSON/XML and also it is widely used.
	4.two types : producer, consumer
		</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Producer</rich_text>
    <rich_text> : this is like a shop that puts its a services on display. To publish our services web service and make its available for others use.
		</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Consumer:</rich_text>
    <rich_text>this is like a customer shoping at the store. It uses the web service by sending requests and get response back.
	5.</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Advantages</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: we can access service in diffrent platforms(windows,linux) and programming languages.they understand each others message. The services can manage many request without slowing down or crashing . they can handle lot of work efficiently.Service Can change and grow independently.If one service changes they won't affect any other service.	
	6.</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Development</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: 
		Implementation: Using framework like spring for SOAP or RESTful services using JAX-RS(Java Api for RESTfull web Services).
		Documentation: swagger provides for clear documentaion for API end points and usage.
		Security: implementing authentication and authorization security for our web services endpoints. (OAuth)
		</rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Examples:</rich_text>
    <rich_text> SOAP is used in enterprise system for complex transaction(banking).
		REST is widely used in mobile application and modern web development.</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
